RG 089:030, State Traffic Commission
Connecticut State Library
State Traffic Commission meeting agendas and minutes
1935-1995
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. State Traffic Commission
17 cubic feet
The State Traffic Commission was established as the legal traffic authority of Connecticut, to provide rules and regulations for the establishment of uniform traffic control signals, devices, signs, and markings for the use of vehicular and pedestrian traffic upon the public highway.
RG089_030
2005-013
Historical Note
The State Traffic Commission was established July 1, 1935, per 1935 Cum. Suppl. sec. 73c, and administratively under the Highway Dept. In 1977, per P.A. 77-614, the Traffic Commission was transferred to the Dept. of Transportation. The Commission was established as the legal traffic authority of Connecticut, to provide rules and regulations for the establishment of uniform traffic control signals, devices, signs, and markings for the use of vehicular and pedestrian traffic upon the public highway.
See also the.
Scope and Content
These records consist solely of meeting agendas and minutes, 1935-1995.
Arrangement
The meeting agendas and minutes are arranged chronologically.
Related Material
RG 089, Dept. of Transportation, 1941-2003, bulk 1973-2003
RG 089:001, State Highway Department, 1894-1975
RG 089:010, State Boundary Line Perambulations, 1965-1997
RG 089:011, Aerial photographs, see the Research Guide to Aerial Photographs at the Connecticut State Library
RG 089:024, Connecticut Transportation Authority, 1956-1973
RG 089:031, Connecticut Public Transportation Commission, 1980-2001
RG 089:032, Transportation Accountability Board, 1986-1987
RG 089:037, Commissioners of Steamship Terminals, 1915
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. State Traffic Commission; Connecticut. Dept. of Transportation
Subjects:
Traffic regulations -- Connecticut; Traffic signs and signals -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Agendas; Minutes
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Meeting agendas and minutes, 1935-1995
  - 1935-1956 (Box 1)
  - 1957 - 1960 (Box 2)
  - 1961 - 1963 (Box 3)
  - 1964 - 1966 (Box 4)
  - 1967 - 1969 October (Box 5)
  - 1969 November - 1971 August (Box 6)
  - 1971 September - 1972 (Box 7)
  - 1973 - 1974 October (Box 8)
  - 1974 November - 1976 June (Box 9)
  - 1976 July - 1978 March (Box 10)
  - 1978 April - 1979 December (Box 11)
  - 1980 January - 1981 December (Box 12)
  - 1982 - 1984 (Box 13)
  - 1985 - 1987 (Box 14)
  - 1988 - 1990 (Box 15)
  - 1991 - 1993 (Box 16)
  - 1994 - 1995 (Box 17)